Guide to the 250th Anniversary Commemoration, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
250th anniversary commemoration, Yale University, records
1951-1951
RU 48
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(1 box)
The records consist of correspondence, news releases, publications, a press book, and letters congratulating Yale on its 250th anniversary.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-A (YRG 2-A), Records of the Yale president's office.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Office of the President, 1951.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, news releases, publications, a press book, and letters congratulating Yale on its 250th anniversary.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by type of material.
Anniversaries; Yale University -- Anniversaries, etc.
- Records concerning Yale's 250th anniversary, 1951; Accession 1951-A-001
  - Correspondence
    - A-K (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - L-Z (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Replies from colleges and universities
    - A-N, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - O-Z, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Oxford and Cambridge (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lists, news releases, seating arrangements (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine, 1951 October - November (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Samples of printed materials (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Greetings from University of Cambridge (Box 2)
  - Greetings from Harvard University (Box 3)
- Press book for the 250th anniversary celebration and alumni convocation of Yale University, 1951; Accession 2005-A-087
  - Press book for the 250th anniversary celebration and alumni convocation of Yale University, 1951 October (Box 1)
- Addition, 1951
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Presumed to have come from the Office of the President
  - Beloit College congratulatory note (Folder 1)
  - Cornell University congratulatory note, 1951 (Folder 1)
  - Hamilton College congratulatory note, 1951 (Folder 1)
  - Oxford congratulations certificate, 1951 (Folder 1)
  - Princeton congratulatory note, 1951 (Folder 1)
  - University of Missouri congratulations, 1951 (Folder 1)
  - Western Reserve College congratulations, 1951 (Folder 1)
  - Borough of Wrexham congratulatory letter, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Columbia University congratulations, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Dartmouth College congratulatory certificate, 1951 (Box 2)
  - "Daughter college" delegates photograph, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Kenyon College congratulatory letter, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Oregon University certificate, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Tulane University congratulatory note, 1951 (Box 2)
  - University of California congratulatory greeting, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Universitat Heidelberg congratulatory letter, 1951 (Box 2)
  - University of Wisconsin congratulatory letter, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Washington University best wishes note, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Wilson College congratulations, 1951 (Box 2)